localeapp.com 2016-05-06

# Privacy Policy | Locale

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Portal47 we have a few fundamental principles:

  1. We don't ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can't stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  2. We don't share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  3. We don't store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
  4. We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what's visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals:

If you have questions about deleting or correcting your personal data please email us [support@localeapp.com](mailto:support@localeapp.com)

It is Portal47’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Portal47 collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request.

Portal47's purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Portal47's visitors use its website.

From time to time, Portal47 may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Portal47 also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments or contributing to projects.

Portal47 only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that contributor IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the relevant project owner.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Portal47’s websites choose to interact with Portal47 in ways that require Portal47 to gather personally-identifying information.

The amount and type of information that Portal47 gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account at [Locale](http://www.localeapp.com/) to provide a username and email address.

Those who engage in transactions with Portal47 – by purchasing access to paid services, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions.

In each case, Portal47 collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfil the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Portal47.

Portal47 does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

## Aggregated Statistics

Portal47 may collect statistics about the behaviour of visitors to its websites. For instance, Portal47 may monitor the most popular projects on the [Locale](http://www.localeapp.com/).

Portal47 may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Portal47 does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Portal47 discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organisations that;

  * need to know that information in order to process it on Portal47’s behalf or to provide services available at Portal47’s websites, and
  * that have agreed not to disclose it to others. 

Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organisations may be located outside of your home country; by using Portal47’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them.

Portal47 will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone.

Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organisations, as described above, Portal47 discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Portal47 believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Portal47, third parties or the public at large.

If you are a registered user of an Locale account and have supplied your email address, Portal47 may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Portal47 and our products.

We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum.

If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

Portal47 takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorised access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns.

Portal47 uses cookies to help Portal47 identify and track visitors, their usage of Portal47 website, and their website access preferences.

Portal47 visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Portal47’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Portal47’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

## Business Transfers

If Portal47, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Portal47 goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party.

You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Portal47 may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

## Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies.

These cookies allow the ad server to recognise your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer.

This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you.

This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Portal47 and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Portal47 may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Portal47’s sole discretion.

Portal47 encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a Locale account, you should also check your project's dashboard for alerts to these changes.

Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

_Thanks to[Wordpress](http://wordpress.com/) for releasing their Privacy Policy under a [Creative Commons Sharealike Licence](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/) which enabled us to repurpose this text for our own use._
